<book>
<l>AN</l>
<l>HEROIC EPISTLE</l>
<l>TO THE RIGHT HONOURABLE</l>
<l>THE LORD CRAVEN.</l>
<l>[PRICE ONE SHILLING.]</l>
<l>AN</l>
<l>HEROIC EPISTLE</l>
<l>TO THE RIGHT HONOURABLE</l>
<l>THE LORD CRAVEN,</l>
<l>On his delivering the following SENTENCE at the COUNTY MEETING at ABINGDON, on TUESDAY November 7, 1775.</l>
<l>"I WILL HAVE IT KNOWN THERE IS RESPECT DUE TO A LORD."</l>
<l>"_Room for my LORD! Virtue stand by and bow._"</l>
<l>Churchill.</l>
<l>THE THIRD EDITION.</l>
<l>_LONDON:_</l>
<l>Printed for JOHN WHEEBLE, No. 22, Fleet-Street.</l>
<l>M,DCC,LXXVI.</l>
<l>AN</l>
<l>HEROIC EPISTLE</l>
<l>TO</l>
<l>LORD CRAVEN.</l>
<p>
Too long have Britain's sons with proud disdain<br/>
Survey'd the gay Patrician's titled train,<br/>
Their various merit scann'd with eye severe,<br/>
Nor learn'd to know the peasant from the peer:<br/>
At length the Gothic ignorance is o'er,<br/>
And vulgar brows shall scowl on LORDS no more;<br/>
Commons shall shrink at each ennobled nod,<br/>
And ev'ry lordling shine a demigod:<br/>
By CRAVEN taught, the humbler herd shall know,<br/>
How high the Peerage, and themselves how low.<br/>
Illustrious Chief, your eloquence divine<br/>
Shall raise the whole right honourable line;<br/>
All shall with joy your bright example view,<br/>
And love the tribe that boasts a son like you;<br/>
While Liberty shall lead you to her throne<br/>
With jocund hand, and claim you for her own.<br/>
</p>
<p>
When warm in youth, on Isis' learned shore,<br/>
You early listen'd to her sacred lore;<br/>
Abhorr'd the dull confinement of the schools,<br/>
Contemn'd their statutes, and despis'd their rules.<br/>
Ev'n when to burst their bonds your ardor fail'd,<br/>
And law, tyrannic law, at last prevail'd,<br/>
Tho' forc'd a while to bend beneath the yoke,<br/>
Its weight your dauntless spirit never broke,<br/>
Still rankled in your breast the fatal wound,<br/>
Tho' years had o'er it roll'd their circling round,<br/>
On [A]SCROPE, tho' late, you rear'd your threat'ning arm,<br/>
And shew'd the will without the pow'r to harm.<br/>
</p>
<p>
With Freedom's warmth, tho' thus your bosom glow'd,<br/>
From no licentious heat the ardour flow'd<br/>
When peaceful leaders rul'd with gentle sway,<br/>
Still were you first their mandates to obey;<br/>
Tho' Proctors, arm'd with all th' insulting pride<br/>
Of legal pow'r, your daring soul defy'd,<br/>
Yet to the ruler of the festive band<br/>
You bow'd, nor scorn'd the toast-master's command;<br/>
Obedient drank each penal draft of wine,<br/>
And only fear'd a salt and water fine.<br/>
</p>
<p>
So burn'd your youthful heart with Freedom's flame,<br/>
Such the fair dawning of your future fame;<br/>
But when by time matur'd, the Peerage spread<br/>
Its dazzling lustre round your honor'd head,<br/>
The sacred fire that warm'd before your breast,<br/>
Blaz'd boldly forth to all mankind confess'd,<br/>
Immortal Liberty with blooming charms,<br/>
Woo'd you so strongly to her heavenly arms,<br/>
So fierce your passion, that you could not bear<br/>
Another vot'ry should her favors share;<br/>
For still your heart Othello's plan approves,<br/>
Nor keeps a corner in the thing it loves<br/>
For others uses; those who madly brave<br/>
Attack the rights you have, or think you have,<br/>
Shall weep their rashness, that in luckless hour,<br/>
Oppos'd th' omnipotence of lordly pow'r.<br/>
When SEYMOUR insolently dar'd invade,<br/>
Manors by your possession sacred made,<br/>
From feasts you deign'd to grace, you wip'd his name,<br/>
And gave him o'er to infamy and shame:<br/>
And when, tho' late, he made a bold appeal<br/>
To arms, from frowning Peers and fawning zeal,<br/>
And dar'd attempt with sacrilegious sword,<br/>
To offer equal combat to a LORD,<br/>
Sudden your noble limbs your coursers bore,<br/>
From Berkshire's hills to Avon's distant shore:<br/>
And eager to preserve from foul disgrace,<br/>
Th' unsullied honors of a noble race,<br/>
Rather than have it said you meanly stood<br/>
To stain your faulchion with Plebeian blood,<br/>
You yielded bravely to a harsher fate,<br/>
And made submissions to the man you hate.<br/>
To save their dignity from scandal's breath,<br/>
Thousands have fearless fac'd approaching death;<br/>
Your dauntless action merits more applause,<br/>
Who courted infamy in honor's cause.<br/>
</p>
<p>
Proceed! proceed! and still our wond'ring eyes<br/>
With deeds magnanimous like these surprize,<br/>
And lest some wretch, phlegmatic, dull, and cold,<br/>
Without applause such actions should behold,<br/>
Aloud to list'ning crowds your worth proclaim,<br/>
Yourself the herald of your deathless fame.<br/>
To spacious Berks your dignity avow,<br/>
From Buscot's meads, to Windsor's lofty brow,<br/>
Till LOVEDEN's daring insolence is o'er,<br/>
And POWNEY cross your fav'rite schemes no more;<br/>
Your sacred game, till lawless SEYMOUR spare,<br/>
Nor hot-brain'd PYE another challenge bear.<br/>
Shall humble Squires presume, by act or word,<br/>
T' oppose the wishes of a mighty LORD;<br/>
On high affairs attempt to give their voice,<br/>
Or in elections e'er avow their choice;<br/>
Pour in your rabble to each factious town,<br/>
And Freedom's sounds, by shouting numbers drown,<br/>
Till Thames' unpeopled waves by READING glide,<br/>
Without one bargeman left to chear the tide;<br/>
And NEWBURY's desart streets lament in vain,<br/>
Their servile inmates gone to swell your train.<br/>
Stout FERDINANDO, your obsequious slave,<br/>
Once a rude ruffian, now a pliant knave,<br/>
With Stentor's voice shall swell your pageant pride,<br/>
And boldly thunder nonsense on your side:<br/>
The gentle Colonel, simpering SELLWOOD too,<br/>
His face with port and patriot-ardor blue,<br/>
With vacant eye shall view your great intent,<br/>
Shall scratch his empty head, and smile assent.<br/>
There too my muse, with rough, tho' honest song,<br/>
Shall chant your virtues to the admiring throng,<br/>
Display your various worth in humble lays,<br/>
And teach the gaping rabble how to praise,<br/>
Re-echo to their ears your fav'rite word,<br/>
And shew respect should always wait MY LORD.<br/>
Perhaps, (indulge your Poet's fairy dream),<br/>
Perhaps my verse adorn'd by such a theme,<br/>
May in some bark, our navy sail t' explore,<br/>
Be safely wafted to the Atlantic shore:<br/>
How will those pious Chiefs delight to hear<br/>
The kindred virtues of a British Peer?<br/>
How will thy deeds enchant, with gentle sway,<br/>
The Patriot sons of Massachuset's Bay?<br/>
For all your ardor fires the illustrious train,<br/>
In Council bold, but bashful on the plain:<br/>
How will their grateful bosoms love the verse,<br/>
Whose honest lines such great exploits rehearse?<br/>
I see their hands prepare the verdant bough,<br/>
I feel their laurel wreaths surround my brow;<br/>
While that long-honour'd strain, whose magic charms<br/>
So oft has called the gallant race to arms,<br/>
Shall now at length give place to newer lays,<br/>
And Yanky-doodle yield to CRAVEN'S praise.<br/>
</p>
THE END.<br/>
</book>